Welcome to another video, in this video we will try to decode this code which we have
actually created by the Cobalt Strike, so when you are attempting any interviews, any
product based companies or any service based companies like MNCs, they will be giving this
kind of encoder and encrypted code to you, and they will ask you to decode this, so that
was the one of the round, they will be contacting, so maximum they will be using the Cobalt
Strike based encoder payloads, so your job is to decode this, so here you can find the text
has been heavily encrypted, sorry encoder, so it was mentioned encoder command, so this is also
a part of a malware analysis, so when you are in a security research team or any lab
team in any of organization, server security based organization, so there will be a separate
lab safety working, so they will be finding all the malware and they will be blocking the hash
in their antivirus products, so let us see try to decode this, so here we can see the code,
so let us copy the code, so I am using one of the website called cyber chief, let me load
the cyber chief, I will do one thing, let me start the Visual Studio too, let me open a new
text file, so this is the, this is the, this 64 code which we have, it is very big, so
let me will go our first up, so here you can find the a equal to equal to, so we will equal
that, so if any of the strings if, if you notify the equal to symbol, then it will be
64, just implement the from day 64 function, so now you can see some weird text format
null null null, you need to remove the null bytes, remove the null bytes, so now you can
find the memory stream and from base explore something something has been written, we will
copy this and we will paste it in a, sorry, we will use a, yeah, we will use this,
so now you can find another code, so from base explore, so we can understand it is a base
64 code which has been encoder and in the end of the line, they mentioned its input output
compression, so compression model will be a gun safe, here you can find g6 stream, so
what we will do, we will take this code, so here you can find, let me take our null bytes,
so we know one thing, this was encoder by a base explore, so we used base 64, so and
it was obfuscator, they used the g6 compression, so d will search for a g6, g6, so here you
can find our two things, g6 and a gun safe, so g6 is still in compressing data using
the defator algorithm, g6 header and gun safe telling decompresses the data which has been
compressed using the defator algorithm, so we know it actually compressed, so we need
decompressed that, so let us take this and here you can find some coding, let will copy
this, so let us see, so this code which was
encrypted, so encoder with the base explore, so no problem, and here you can find a few things,
the xr, b xr 35, so xr is an encryption method, so if you want to know about xr, just
google, and we will see, so here you can find xr is an encryption method, so the payload
has been encrypted, and if there is an encryption we need a key to decrypt, anyway, so
you can see the key, b xr 35, 35 is the key anyway, so b will take the, let us see more
the gun safe, so now the base 64 has been removed, let us decode this, so xr and you need
to give the key, so we know the key is 35, and it was in the hex form, and let me change
it to decimal, so now you can find a few things, so you can see the user agent is a Mozilla
compatibility Windows NT, 5.1, and you can see the protector IP, so that is our IP, the
cobalt sake IP which we have created, 18.27 here, so now you can confirm, so this payload
was connecting to the 18.27 and the user agent is this one, so we know this was connecting
to the, once the payload has been executed, the base 64, I mean this code, I mean once
the evil.html has been executed on the machine, so it will execute and it will connect
to this IP okay, so as a part of our commendations you can block this IP in a firewall
or anything, so that will stop the attacks, that will stop the reverse connections okay,
so these are the things you can investigate when there is a encoder or an encrypted command
which was given okay, so this is the CT from, they will be asking if you are attending
any new team-based entities okay, so we will hop off this video and we will discuss
our next task, things in our next video okay, see you guys bye bye.